So, hello everyone, in this video, what we are going to do is, we are going to work with
Jason, we are going to, okay.
So what basically happens is that suppose for example, when you are logging a particular
website, okay.
So when you click that log in button, you log into the website.
So this login has a session, okay.
So when you are logging into a particular site, it has a session.
Like after how much time, the thing is going to expire, like for example, if you are logging
in a particular website, okay.
So sometimes you have seen is like that, like when you are accessing a particular site and
when you have logged in, it expires after a particular period of time.
So that is why we use Jason, we are talking in that case, to set expiry time, like after
how much or what is the limit at which when we refresh the website, the particular token,
which is assigned to a particular user, gets expired, okay.
So that is why we use Jason, we have token.
So if you take a bookish definition of for it, so I can search it for you, okay.
Like let's use copilot.
So what is Jason web token?
So it will display some results, like Jason web token is secure, compact, way to transmit
information between two parties, often used for authentication and authorization in web
applications.
Like it has header component, it has a payload and it has a signature ensures the token
hasn't been tampered with created by encoding the header and payload, then signing with
the secret or a private key, okay.
So how JWT works?
So authentication part as you can see here, like after login, the server generates a JWT
and sends it to the client, okay.
Then client uses the client stores the token, often in the local storage of cookies
and sends it with each request.
The server checks the signature to confirm the token is valid and grants access and that
is how some login or logout sessions work.
So you can read more about this, so you get a better idea.
So for now I'm going to just code it, alright.
So in this live folder, as you can see, I'm going to create one file which is called as
a token.
Let's name is a token.js and after this token.js we are going to import our JWT.
So JWT package from Jason web token.
Now let's export it, so export const token, JNA, and equals to, we have a user ID and
then we have RES response and we are going to use this called a function and we are going
to just declare one const token equals to JWT dot sign.
So here in this case we are going to create a digital signature of it, like whenever you
log in or whenever we resign into a particular application we are going to assign you
to some kind of a digital signature which is also called as token, okay.
So it has a particular expiry time, like it has a H, like after how much time it is
going to expire, what is the session ID and all that like payload and data and all that
stuff.
So you can read more about it, but basic overview I have given you, like high over V,
high overview, okay.
So user ID and then what we are going to do is we are going to just make one particular
secret key, okay.
So secret key we can make this in a dot in weak package, so what you can do it, like secret
key and secret key would be something around whatever, whatever you can make of it.
So control is and then now go inside of this token.js and what we can do is process.env.c
key, so we are going to fetch that secret key from the dot in v file and we are going
to set it expiration.
So whatever the time this token is going to expire.
So suppose we are going to name it as 7 days, so it is going to expire in the 7 days.
So now what we can do is we are going to take the response and we are going to set the
key as a JWT and we are going to pass this token which we have created here.
So response dot cookie JWT token and now here we are going to set the max age, so max age.
So max age would be the 7 days, okay, 7 into 24 hours, so they are 24 hours in particular
day, one particular day, so 24 into 60 into 60, so 60 minutes for one hour, 60 second and
then we are going to assign this as 1000 milliseconds.
So now HTTP only, so we are going to pass this as true.
So if this website is what follows the HTTP protocol, so accordingly we are setting this
as HTTP only values are true and same site, same site, same site and we are going to assign
this as a strict, okay, so these are some values, so the same site what it actually does
is it is kind of checking the like cross verifying, say that cookie is across like cross
sites, okay, so like that only and it also enhances the security of one particular website
as it checks for the CRSAP attacks as well, so you can read about that article, this article
when you go to this particular website, okay, so now control S, so this is the implementation,
so I have searched you one thing, you are like same site, same site is a cookie attribute
that controls whether a browser sends cookies along with cross site requests, okay, and
it was introduced to improve the security and privacy by reducing risk like cross site requests
for the CSRF and unwanted tracking, so you can read out is like strict, lax and none
and why is it is used, like for example to enhance the privacy for default security and
prevents CSRF attacks, so you can read here only, okay.